

linkedin: /riegerdaniel dan.j.rieger@gmail.com drieggs.github.io 631-338-6688

As a UX designer, my desires for discovering new things and advancing my skills is insatiable. I first developed my design skills by teaching myself UI/UX design and front-end coding while bootstrapping several startups. Then I honed those skills through the User Experience Design Immersive training at General Assembly. Working long hours in a small team has taught me to quickly adjust to new environments and has allowed me understand how all the parts of a company need to work together.

Design Experience

Contract UI Designer

SKM LLC, Southampton NY

- Contracted to design 7 different website UI perfect templates after establishing good UX practices for all of them.
- Created several different sets of wireframes after conducting user research; each wireframe became 2-3 different UI designs.

Contract UX Designer / Front-end Dev

Sadotech, Long Island NY

- Conducted user research in order to determine the cause of a low ecommerce conversion rate on the company's new site.
- Completed a full site redesign based on the research, then implemented the new design through HTML/CSS as well as Liquid (Shopify language).
- Monitored google analytics to track different e-commerce funnels; the conversion rate increased from 2.1% to 4.3% after the redesign.

Co-Founder & Director of Growth

12/2013-11/2014

2/27/17 - 4/2/17

11/3/16 - 2/20/17

Besso Labs LLC, Chicago IL

- Created wireframes, prototypes, and designed/coded UI for multiple cross-platform mobile applications.
- Analyzed user data to identify opportunities for improvement in application capability and design for the development team.

Other Experience

Chief Marketing Officer

Basilar Technologies LLC, Chicago, IL

Digital Marketing Director

Kinetik Entertainment LLC, Chicago, IL

8/2012-6/2013

10/2010-7/2012

Skills

User Centered Skills

User Research
User Interviews
Competitive Analysis
User Flows
Usability Testing
Story Boarding
Persona Creation

Design Skills

Wireframing
Prototyping
Lean/agile Design Methods
Illustrator
Sketch3
Balsamiq

Dev Skills

HTML
CSS
Javascript basics
Liquid basics
Google Analytics

Education

Northwestern University

Chicago IL, 2009-2013
Bachelor of Science
Major: Psychology

General Assembly

New York NY, 2016

Immersive Program

User Experience Design